Daniel Sperry | fullstack web developer

Phone: 503.724.1893

email: danny.sperry@gmail.com

4 years ago I taught myself the basics of web development. I've helped create beautiful brand sites for FINE, I've mentored team members, documented company and project processes, and I've built JSON APIs used for mobile platforms for Metova. Recently, I've been growing with Rails 5.1 and ReactJS/VueJS. I would love more opportunities to lead/assist teams as well.

For me, it's about building usable products that are reliable for customers and extendable for new developers to jump into quickly.

EXPERIENCE

07/2016 - present *freelance* **FULL STACK DEVELOPER** - *Remote*

- Fullstack developer/project manager for a local business's brand site with React/Rails 5.1 on Heroku.
- Worked with 3rd party developer to integrate POS script to load a menu of products.
- Taught myself React, Redux, webpack, and became familiar with ES6 syntax

03/2015 - 12/2016 *Metova Inc* **FULL STACK DEVELOPER** - *Remote*

- Lead Developer on <u>www.storyclip.com</u> with team of 3.
 - Lead SCRUM meetings and managed team efficiency
 - Built JSON API for mobile devices to send video clips
 - Used ffmpeg to merge video clips together
- Web Developer/Project Manager on small 8-week retainers for MVP

builds.

- Front-end Developer on team of 10 that worked on a year 9 month contract with AngularJS audio streaming app
 - Built Windows app with WinJS from web code
 - Added test suite and got tested code coverage up to 75%.
 - Upgraded Angular from v1.2 to v1.6(latest was v1.7 before I left that project)

11/2014 - 2/2015 FINE Design Group **RAILS DEVELOPER** - Portland, OR

- Promoted to mid-level developer
- Helped junior developers

EDUCATION

2013 Code Fellows iOS - 8 week iOS bootcamp based in Seattle, WA. **2012** - **2013** Self taught - HTML/CSS and Ruby/Rails using online resources and books.